AI coding assistants. We love them, but
they're actually pretty terrible at
validating their own work unless you
give them a framework to follow. And
that is what I've been experimenting
with for hundreds of hours at this
point, getting really specific for the
coding agent. So, it's not skimping out
on the validation. It does that all the
time. And so that it's actually testing
the application as a user would. And so,
I have packaged up my entire validation
process that I go through for most of my
AI generated code. and I put it into a
single command. This diagram that you're
looking at here outlines everything that
I got packaged up for you. And the best
part is this is pretty general. And so
I'll have a link in the description to
this command. You could literally go and
run this on any codebase right now as
long as it has a frontend. And so I want
to explain right now how this command
works and help you understand some of
the ideas that go into this so that you
can improve your own workflows for your
coding agents to validate their own
work. There's a lot of golden nuggets
that I have in here for you. I've been
doing a lot of iterating on this. And
the reason this is so important is
because coding agents now are generating
code so incredibly quickly that it's
almost impossible for us to keep up with
the validation. And AI generated code is
still your responsibility. So you need
to validate. I'm not going to be a
proponent of Vive coding. And so really
what this workflow is doing is just
delegating as much of the validation as
possible to the coding agent. This is
the workflow that I'll show you in a
little bit here, just a sneak peek
preview. And so we want it to fix as
many issues up front, even point us to
where we should address things ourself,
so that by the time control passes back
to us, there's just a lot less of that
mental burden, that drag of having to
review hundreds or even thousands of
lines of code that was generated in the
last 20 minutes. And man, let me tell
you, it feels like a weight lifted off
my shoulders using this kind of process,
especially with the evolution that I'm
currently at. That's why I'm so excited
to show this to you right now. It's why
I'm calling it the self-healing AI
coding workflow. It's not that coding
agents are going to be perfect with
this, but it does come pretty close.
I've been really impressed with the
results recently. So, I'll show you each
little component of this workflow very
quickly, how it works. We'll see it in
action. and I'll also talk about how you
can incorporate something like this into
your own AI coding workflows. So, here
is the command or the claude code skill
that we're going to be using right now.
And so, I'll link to this exact skill.md
in the description if you just want to
take this command, use it for yourself
on any codebase right away. It works out
of the box. It even automatically
installs the Verscel agent browser CLI.
This is the browser automation tool that
I've been leaning on very heavily
recently. I also made a video on it
already that I'll link to right here.
And so this is a big part of the
process, but it's going to work for
really any coding agent as well. You
could also change this up to work with
any other browser automation tool like
Chrome DevTools, MCP, whatever you want
to use. And it's really just giving a
lot of specificity, a framework to the
coding agent for how to do research,
what should the flow look like for self-
validation. And I figured instead of
going through this entire markdown
document, it'd be a lot better for me to
explain things more visually. So that's
why I have this diagram that I'll go
over really quickly so you can
understand all the components that I
have built into this. So for your own
agentic engineering, there are two ways
that you can use this workflow. You can
either just use it whenever you want
outside of any feature development. So
maybe you just want to at some certain
point run full end toend testing on your
codebase. That's what I'll cover first
as a live demo. And then the other way
that I'll speak to more towards the end
of the video is you can build this
workflow directly in your feature
implementation process. So after the
coding agent writes any kind of feature,
it's going to dive right into this to do
regression testing and making sure that
what it just built is working well. So
first of all, since this is a command,
we are going to invoke it with /2e test.
And that will kick off the six-step
workflow that we have here. Starting
with our prerec check. So because we are
using a browser automation tool very
heavily in this process I do require you
to have a frontend for your codebase
which for me personally that is a
majority of my applications probably is
for you as well which is why I'm saying
we can use this command for pretty much
every single codebase. If you want to do
any kind of testing for backendon apps
definitely requires a different kind of
workflow that I'll definitely cover in
future content. Another check here is if
you're running on Windows because if you
are you can't use the Verscell agent
browser CLI but you can simply just use
WSL. That's what I'm literally doing in
this video. So we check all the prerexs.
If we are good then we go to phase one,
our research phase. So the point of this
phase is to ground ourself in the
application. what are all the ways that
users would actually use this
application so that we can test all of
that and then also understanding our
data schema and just how we're working
with the database overall because almost
every single full stack application is
working with a database and so the cool
part about this is we have three sub
agents that run in parallel. This is
built directly into the workflow. So one
agent is going to understand the
structure of the codebase and how users
will use it. another understands the
database schema and then the other one
is doing the code review part of our
validation. So the rest of this process
is more let's go through the application
as a user would. But this sub aent is
going to find things like logic errors
that we have in our code. And so all
three sub aents run in parallel. And
then the research is compiled in the
context for our primary agent. And then
at that point we are ready to get into
our full endto-end testing. And so we
instruct the agent to start the dev
server. So it'll spin up the entire
application. So it's ready to go to the
URL. And then it's going to define a
task list here. And so each one of the
tasks is going to be one of the user
journeys that we want it to test. Making
sure we can sign in, making sure that we
can edit our profile or many other
things that will get pretty specific to
your codebase. But it'll figure that out
in real time based on its understanding
here. Okay, what are each of the tasks
that we have to lay out? And it'll
really spend a good amount of time with
each one of them. So then next with our
workflow, we pretty much have a for loop
built directly in because we're going to
look at this task list and we're going
to pull out each of the user journeys
and knock them out one at a time in a
very comprehensive way. So just giving
you a little bit of a demonstration here
for what the timeline looks like. This
is what our coding agent is going to be
going through. So it's going to use a
mix of the agent browser CLI to navigate
the website and database queries to make
sure that things are looking good in the
back end as we are creating updating and
deleting records. I am being specific to
Postgress here because currently I am
using Neon with Postgress but you can
really use any database and the command
will adapt itself. And so as an example
here the agent will take a snapshot.
This is how it understands what we
currently have in the page. Then it'll
query the database to make sure things
are looking good. interact with a
certain element and verify like if
there's a record that was supposed to be
created for example and then it'll also
take screenshots along the way. So not
only can it verify that the flows are
working correctly, but also that the UI
looks good because coding agents these
days can analyze images. So we'll have a
bunch of PGs that it'll create along the
way and store in a directory for us to
review after. So the screenshots are
awesome for the agent to review itself,
but then also for us to validate after
that the end toend testing really is
complete. And so at this point, the
coding agent is going to check its work
and it's going to figure out is there
any big issues that we need to address
here. If there is anything that is
entirely blocking the coding agent from
really validating the user journey, then
it will fix the code, retest, take new
screenshots, and validate and do this in
a loop until the user journey is
complete. Now, the really important
distinction to make here is that there
still will be remaining issues after the
endto-end testing. In fact, there are
usually more remaining issues than ones
that are fixed because I have
specifically prompted the coding agent
to only fix the big blockers. And so for
all of the other more, you know,
moderate or minor issues, I want to work
with the coding agent to figure out
like, do I want to address this and how
do I want to do so? So, it's only fixing
this stuff to get it to the point where
it can test the entire user journey. And
then once it does that, it'll take it
from the top and just go through the
next user journey that we have in the
task list. So very systematically
knocking these out one at a time, doing
some responsive checking at the end,
just a lighter like go through the pages
and make sure it looks good on mobile,
tablet, and desktop. And then it gives
us the end toend report at the end. And
this is very important. I'm not just
telling it to share with the user what
happened willy-nilly. I have a lot of
structure built at the bottom of the
prompt, the bottom of the skill.md. So
it's always outputting to me in the
exact same way every time. Here is what
we fixed. Here are the issues that were
remaining. And here is everything that I
went through. And so the goal here is
with the report combined with the
screenshots, I can really go through
things super quickly and make sure the
agent truly did a good job identifying
all the user journeys and going through
them. And then optionally, it can output
to a markdown report. So at this point,
the context window is going to be pretty
bloated with the coding agent going
through all this testing. So if there's
anything more that I want to work with
the agent to reason about and address, I
want to do that in a new context window.
So, I'll take the report from the output
here, send that into a new session with
my coding agent. The sponsor of today's
video is Bright Data, the platform that
unlocks the web for your AI agents, and
it's built to handle hundreds of agents
that you have running in parallel. So,
in this video, we've been focusing on
browser automation for local host. There
is no anti-bot protection. But when your
agents need to access the real internet,
things like LinkedIn profiles,
e-commerce sites, all of these sites are
actively trying to block your agent.
That is why you need bright data. And
the way it works is genuinely
impressive. Your requests from your
agents are routed through 150 million
residential IPs. Captions are solved
automatically. Browser fingerprints are
rotated. Your agent becomes a real
person. And Bright Data has an MCP
server that makes it super easy to get
started. They also have an API. That's
what I'm using for this demo really
quick to show you the power of bright
data getting structured public data on
demand. So, for example, I can say I'm
looking for 10 software engineers in
Minneapolis. And watch, look at all the
logs. It's solved the captures
automatically. It's pulling LinkedIn
information. So, I have all their
profiles. I can research an individual
person. Now, this is just a
demonstration. There are a million
different things that you can do with
bright data. pulling any kind of
information even from sources like
LinkedIn that are usually really hard to
crawl. Now, 14 of the top 20 AI labs are
already running their agents through
bright data. Over 100 million
interactions go through their platform
every day. So, they really are the most
reliable solution when you need real
time access to the web for your agents.
Plus, you can use code Cole Medine. I
also have a link in the description to
get your first $20 of credits for free.
So, definitely check out Bright Data.
All right, so let's go ahead and do a
live demo now that we understand how the
command works, all the components of it.
And so I have the skill.md right here in
my local repository for an application
that I built in the last video on my
channel. So I built this link and bio
page builder. It's kind of like linkree
where you can design your own website
where you put all your links up. You can
send this to people like check this out.
This is where you can go to see all of
my socials and things like that. So this
is the application that we're testing
here. There's quite a bit built into
this for authentication and managing
different themes and being able to
create your own links. And so we're
going to have quite a few user journeys
to go through here. And so I'll do /e2
test. No parameters or anything. And if
you're using a coding agent that doesn't
support commands, then you can literally
just point it to the skill.md tell it to
read that as its prompt and execute
those instructions. And so I'll go ahead
and send this off and it's going to
start right away by checking those
prerexs. So it'll make sure I have the
RCell agent browser CLI that I'm running
on Linux or in this case in WSL and then
pretty soon here it'll kick off the sub
agents for research. So take a look at
this. It's kicking off the first one to
understand the app structure and
journeys. Now the next one to understand
the database schema and then in just a
second here we'll see the code review
one. There we go. The bunk hunting code
analysis. And so I'm obviously not going
to go through this entire thing with
you. So let me pause and come back once
it goes on to the next stage. So I'll
show you all the important stuff here.
All right, very good. We can see that
all three of the sub aents have finished
and now it goes on to the next step of
starting our entire application and it
knows how to do this like the exact
command to run because it's one of the
things that this sub aent finds for us.
And so even if your application has a
couple of steps like you have docker
containers that you have to spin up,
it's still going to figure out all of
that. And then it'll even run into some
of these issues once in a while where it
has to self-correct. And so don't worry,
you might see a lot of errors throughout
the entire process. Like right here, it
tried to visit the site before it was
compiled and started as an Nex.js app.
And so it corrects itself. It waits a
while. Finally, the server's up. Now we
are using the agent browser CLI to visit
it. Taking a screenshot here as well. We
could already take a look at this if we
want to watch its progress as it is
validating. And then here is our task
list. So now that it visited the website
at first just to get its graphs. Now
it's going through all of the user
journeys. And this is the part that
takes the longest for sure because we
have that for loop. We're doing quite a
bit to validate every single one of the
tasks that we have here. And so we'll
see a combination of the agent browser
and whatever calls it's going to make in
order to visit the database and validate
our records. All right. Right. So now
we're getting to some of the interesting
parts of the validation where it has to
do write operations from within the user
interface. And so for example, updating
our profile for this website. And so
it's going to save and then verify the
database update. So we see it take a
snapshot so it understands. Okay, here
is the save button. Now let me click
that. Now let me take a screenshot. Read
the screenshot to make sure that we have
a good UX of saving. It says we save. We
have a pop-up everything like that. And
then make a call to the database. So it
creates a query here to make sure that
the record is confirmed. The profile is
updated with the new display name, bio,
and avatar URL. So it's looking good in
the front end and it's looking good in
our database. And so just going to the
Neon console really quickly here.
There's just a few tables that I have
for this application. So profiles, this
is where we just made an update, right?
So you can see here that we have some of
these E2E test users that were created.
So the coding agent creates a brand new
user, making sure it can update profiles
and then go in and create link items for
that profile tied to the right profile.
Like there's a lot that happens with the
database under the hood and if there's
any issues there, it might not
necessarily be reflected in the front
end, which is why it's really important
that we're doing this level of
validation as well. And then while we're
in the Neon dashboard, one thing I want
to mention really quickly is when we're
doing this kind of endto-end testing and
we're building all these fake profiles
and links and just database entries in
general, it kind of bloats our database.
Even with a dev database, we might not
want to have all those records just
sitting around. And so one thing that I
like doing with Neon is creating a
branch. So this is something specific to
Neon and how they work with Postgress.
we can make these branches where it'll
essentially take a snapshot of our
current data and then give us this
secondary database that we can do
whatever the heck we want with and then
we can delete that go back to our main
branch whenever we want and so that way
I can just create this you know like end
to end test to and then this is the
database that I'm connected to for my
end toend test and you could even build
this directly into the workflow if you
want I'm not doing that right now
because I want this to be more of a
general workflow that works no matter
your database but there are some pretty
powerful things you can do to keep your
test in isolation, keeping your database
clean while still giving your agent full
reign over your database to create
records and validate records, everything
it has to do. All right, take a look at
this. Our validation is done and it
actually fixed quite a few things during
its end toend testing and then some
other issues that we'll need to address
with our agent later. So, it found some
from its end to end testing and then
also some from the bug hunt sub aent
that ran towards the beginning. We have
our end toend screenshots folder. So we
can also validate a lot of these things
to make sure that it really did all the
testing that we expect it to. But yeah,
this is looking super super good. And
then it also asks us if we'd want to
create a markdown to send into another
coding agent to address these issues.
And so from here you can take it as you
want. You can address each one of these
issues one at a time. You could just
send this entire markdown into another
coding agent. Entirely up to you. But
the important thing here is that we
found even the small issues like this is
so detailed. I love the specificity that
this workflow gives our coding agents.
The kinds of things that the agent is
really never going to catch by itself or
at least very rarely. So one last golden
nugget that I want to cover with you
really quickly is how can we use this
end toend test skill directly in our
feature development. So, in the last
video on my channel that I already
linked to, I covered my full process for
AI coding with green field development.
And the PIV loop is the core framework
here. Plan, implement, and validate. And
what I always do for my planning is I
create a structured markdown document
that outlines everything that we need to
build and the entire validation strategy
before we go into implementation. And
this is our opportunity to specify. We
can literally just tell the agent, I
want you to use the endto-end test skill
after you've written the code to test
things in a very comprehensive way. And
so for the skill that I have linked in
the GitHub repo, I've actually disabled
model invocation. You can do this with
all claude code skills. So if I remove
this line, you can do that yourself.
Then the agent can use the end toend
test skill. That's just kind of a safety
cuz most of the time you might just want
to invoke this yourself. But you remove
that line and then and I covered this in
the last video course. So I have my plan
feature command. This is where I outline
the exact structure for my plans that I
want to send into implementation. So we
can just add a line here. So I have the
validation commands. I have a section
for any additional validation. This is
exactly the template that I have in the
last video. So we could just change this
and say use the E2E test skill to do
comprehensive testing. Right? Like
literally that simple. That's all we
have to do. And so now it's going to
basically use this as a subskll. So it's
kind of a subworkflow as a part of this
la larger implementation workflow which
you have to be careful about token usage
here. And that really is the last
warning that I have for you for this
entire process. It is somewhat
tokenheavy and it's going to take a
while. So it's definitely the kind of
thing where you want to send this off
and then work on something else. Step
away from your computer, whatever it is.
Just let this go. But the point of it is
not to be fast. The point of it is to be
comprehensive. And so the time I have to
wait for this to finish and the tokens
that I have to spend, it's worth it to
me. In fact, I think it's saving me
tokens in the end because it's finding
all these issues that otherwise I'd have
to deal with with my coding agents later
on. And I've run this dozens of times in
the last week and I haven't even hit the
rate limit for my Claude Code Max
subscription. So it's pretty token
efficient overall. mainly why it takes
so long is just because we have to wait
for all of these uh you know page
interactions and so sometimes it'll like
run asleep after clicks on a button to
wait for it to load things like that so
it is pretty token efficient overall so
yeah I would encourage you to take this
skill this command just apply it on some
codebase with a front end right now I
think you'll be pretty impressed with
the kinds of things that it can find the
issues that it will surface for you and
so if you appreciated this video and
you're looking forward to more things on
AI coding and self-healing AI coding
workflows. I'd really appreciate a like
and a subscribe. And with that, I will
see you in the next video.